{
    "Maths": [
        {
            "question_number": 1,
            "question": "Let circle C be the image of x^2 + y^2 - 2x + 4y - 4 = 0 in the line 2x - 3y + 5 = 0 and A be the point on C such that OA is parallel to x-axis and A lies on the right hand side of the centre O of C. If B(α, β), with β < 4, lies on C such that the length of the arc AB is (1/6)th of the perimeter of C, then β - sqrt(3)α is equal to",
            "options": [
                "3+√3",
                "4",
                "4-√3",
                "3"
            ],
            "answer": "4"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 2,
            "question": "Let in a triangle ABC, the length of the side AC be 6, the vertex B be (1,2,3) and the vertices A, C lie on the line (x-6)/3 = (y-7)/2 = (z-7)/-2. Then the area (in sq. units) of triangle ABC is:",
            "options": [
                "17",
                "21",
                "56",
                "42"
            ],
            "answer": "21"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 3,
            "question": "Let the product of the focal distances of the point (√3, 1/2) on the ellipse x^2/a^2 + y^2/b^2 = 1 (a > b), be 7/4. Then the absolute difference of the eccentricities of two such ellipses is",
            "options": [
                "(1-√3)/√2",
                "(3-2√2)/(2√3)",
                "(3-2√2)/(3√2)",
                "(1-2√2)/√3"
            ],
            "answer": "(3-2√2)/(2√3)"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 4,
            "question": "2x - y + z = 4; 5x + λy + 3z = 12; 100x - 47y + μz = 212. If the system of equations has infinitely many solutions, then μ - 2λ is equal to",
            "options": [
                "57",
                "59",
                "55",
                "56"
            ],
            "answer": "57"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 5,
            "question": "For some n ≠ 10, let the coefficients of the 5th, 6th and 7th terms in the binomial expansion of (1 + x)^{n+4} be in A.P. Then the largest coefficient in the expansion of (1 + x)^{n+4} is:",
            "options": [
                "20",
                "10",
                "35",
                "70"
            ],
            "answer": "35"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 6,
            "question": "The product of all the rational roots of the equation (x^2 - 9x + 11)^2 - (x-4)(x-5) = 3, is equal to",
            "options": [
                "14",
                "21",
                "28",
                "7"
            ],
            "answer": "14"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 7,
            "question": "Let the line passing through the points (-1,2,1) and parallel to the line (x-1)/2 = (y+1)/3 = z/4 intersect the line (x+2)/3 = (y-3)/2 = (z-4)/1 at the point P. Then the distance of P from the point Q(4,-5,1) is",
            "options": [
                "5",
                "5√5",
                "5√6",
                "10"
            ],
            "answer": "5√5"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 8,
            "question": "Let the lines 3x - 4y - α = 0, 8x - 11y - 33 = 0, and 2x - 3y + λ = 0 be concurrent. If the image of the point (1,2) in the line 2x - 3y + λ = 0 is (57/13, -40/13), then |αλ| is equal to",
            "options": [
                "84",
                "113",
                "91",
                "101"
            ],
            "answer": "91"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 9,
            "question": "If α and β are the roots of the equation 2z^2 - 3z - 2i = 0, where i = √-1, then 16·Re[(α^{19} + β^{19} + α^{11} + β^{11})/(α^{15} + β^{15})]·Im[(α^{19} + β^{19} + α^{11} + β^{11})/(α^{15} + β^{15})] is equal to",
            "options": [
                "441",
                "398",
                "312",
                "409"
            ],
            "answer": "441"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 10,
            "question": "For a statistical data x1, x2, ..., x10 of 10 values, a student obtained the mean as 5.5 and sum_{i=1}^{10} x_i^2 = 371. He later found that he had noted two values in the data incorrectly as 4 and 5, instead of the correct values 6 and 8, respectively. The variance of the corrected data is",
            "options": [
                "9",
                "5",
                "7",
                "4"
            ],
            "answer": "7"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 11,
            "question": "The area of the region {(x, y): x^2 + 4x + 2 ≤ y ≤ |x+2|} is equal to",
            "options": [
                "7",
                "5",
                "24/5",
                "20/3"
            ],
            "answer": "20/3"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 12,
            "question": "Let S_n = 1/2 + 1/6 + 1/12 + 1/20 + ... up to n terms. If the sum of the first six terms of an A.P. with first term -p and common difference p is sqrt(2026 S_{2025}), then the absolute difference between 20th and 15th terms of the A.P. is",
            "options": [
                "20",
                "90",
                "45",
                "25"
            ],
            "answer": "25"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 13,
            "question": "Let f: R - {0} → R be a function such that f(x) - 6f(1/x) = 35/(3x) - 5/2. If lim_{x→0} (1/(αx) + f(x)) = β; α, β ∈ R, then α + 2β is equal to",
            "options": [
                "5",
                "3",
                "4",
                "6"
            ],
            "answer": "4"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 14,
            "question": "If I(m, n) = ∫₀¹ x^{m-1}(1-x)^{n-1} dx, m, n > 0, then I(9,14) + I(10,13) is",
            "options": [
                "I(19,27)",
                "I(9,1)",
                "I(1,13)",
                "I(9,13)"
            ],
            "answer": "I(9,13)"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 15,
            "question": "A and B alternately throw a pair of dice. A wins if he throws a sum of 5 before B throws a sum of 8, and B wins if he throws a sum of 8 before A throws a sum of 5. The probability, that A wins if A makes the first throw, is",
            "options": [
                "8/17",
                "9/19",
                "9/17",
                "8/19"
            ],
            "answer": "9/17"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 16,
            "question": "Let f(x) = (2^{x+2} + 16)/(2^{2x+1} + 2^{x+4} + 32). Then the value of 8(f(1/15) + f(2/15) + ... + f(59/15)) is equal to",
            "options": [
                "92",
                "118",
                "102",
                "108"
            ],
            "answer": "118"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 17,
            "question": "Let y = y(x) be the solution of the differential equation (xy - 5x^2 sqrt(1+x^2)) dx + (1 + x^2) dy = 0, y(0) = 0. Then y(√3) is equal to",
            "options": [
                "sqrt(15/2)",
                "5√3/2",
                "2√2",
                "sqrt(14/3)"
            ],
            "answer": "5√3/2"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 18,
            "question": "lim_{x→0} csc x (sqrt(2 cos^2 x + 3 cos x) - sqrt(cos^2 x + sin x + 4)) is:",
            "options": [
                "0",
                "1/√15",
                "1/(2√5)",
                "-1/(2√5)"
            ],
            "answer": "-1/(2√5)"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 19,
            "question": "Consider the region R = {(x, y): x ≤ y ≤ 9 - (11/3)x^2, x ≥ 0}. The area, of the largest rectangle of sides parallel to the coordinate axes and inscribed in R, is:",
            "options": [
                "730/119",
                "625/111",
                "821/123",
                "567/121"
            ],
            "answer": "567/121"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 20,
            "question": "Let a = i + 2j + 3k, b = 3i + j - k and c be three vectors such that c is coplanar with a and b. If the vector c is perpendicular to b and a·c = 5, then |c| is equal to",
            "options": [
                "sqrt(11/6)",
                "1/(3√2)",
                "16",
                "18"
            ],
            "answer": "sqrt(11/6)"
        }
    ],
    "Physics": [
        {
            "question_number": 26,
            "question": "During the transition of electron from state A to state C of a Bohr atom, the wavelength of emitted radiation is 2000 Å and it becomes 6000 Å when the electron jumps from state B to state C. Then the wavelength of the radiation emitted during the transition of electrons from state A to state B is",
            "options": [
                "4000 Å",
                "2000 Å",
                "3000 Å",
                "6000 Å"
            ],
            "answer": "3000 Å"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 27,
            "question": "Consider the following statements: A. The junction area of solar cell is made very narrow compared to a photo diode. B. Solar cells are not connected with any external bias. C. LED is made of lightly doped p-n junction. D. Increase of forward current results in continuous increase of LED light intensity. E. LEDs have to be connected in forward bias for emission of light. Choose the correct answer from the options given below:",
            "options": [
                "B, E Only",
                "B, D, E Only",
                "A, C Only",
                "A, C, E Only"
            ],
            "answer": "B, E Only"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 28,
            "question": "An alternating current is given by I=I_A sin ωt + I_B cos ωt. The r.m.s current will be",
            "options": [
                "|I_A + I_B|/√2",
                "√((I_A^2 + I_B^2)/2)",
                "√(I_A^2 + I_B^2)",
                "√(I_A^2 + I_B^2)/2"
            ],
            "answer": "√((I_A^2 + I_B^2)/2)"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 29,
            "question": "A car of mass m moves on a banked road having radius r and banking angle θ. To avoid slipping from banked road, the maximum permissible speed of the car is v0. The coefficient of friction μ between the wheels of the car and the banked road is",
            "options": [
                "μ=(v0^2 + rg tanθ)/(rg + v0^2 tanθ)",
                "μ=(v0^2 - rg tanθ)/(rg - v0^2 tanθ)",
                "μ=(v0^2 - rg tanθ)/(rg + v0^2 tanθ)",
                "μ=(v0^2 + rg tanθ)/(rg - v0^2 tanθ)"
            ],
            "answer": "μ=(v0^2 - rg tanθ)/(rg + v0^2 tanθ)"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 30,
            "question": "A satellite is launched into a circular orbit of radius R around the earth. A second satellite is launched into an orbit of radius 1.03R. The time period of revolution of the second satellite is larger than the first one approximately by",
            "options": [
                "9%",
                "3%",
                "4.5%",
                "2.5%"
            ],
            "answer": "4.5%"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 31,
            "question": "An ideal gas goes from an initial state to final state. During the process, the pressure of gas increases linearly with temperature. A. The work done by gas during the process is zero. B. The heat added to gas is different from change in its internal energy. C. The volume of the gas is increased. D. The internal energy of the gas is increased. E. The process is isochoric (constant volume process) Choose the correct answer from the options given below:",
            "options": [
                "E Only",
                "A, B, C, D Only",
                "A, D, E Only",
                "A, C Only"
            ],
            "answer": "A, D, E Only"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 32,
            "question": "An electron of mass m with an initial velocity v = v0 i (v0 > 0) enters an electric field E = -E0 k. If the initial de Broglie wavelength is λ0, the value after time t would be",
            "options": [
                "λ0/√(1 + e^2 E0^2 t^2 / m^2 v0^2)",
                "λ0 √(1 + e^2 E0^2 t^2 / m^2 v0^2)",
                "λ0/√(1 - e^2 E0^2 t^2 / m^2 v0^2)",
                "λ0"
            ],
            "answer": "λ0/√(1 + e^2 E0^2 t^2 / m^2 v0^2)"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 33,
            "question": "What is the relative decrease in focal length of a lens for an increase in optical power by 0.1 D from 2.5D ? ['D' stands for dioptre]",
            "options": [
                "0.01",
                "0.04",
                "0.40",
                "0.1"
            ],
            "answer": "0.04"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 34,
            "question": "A force F = α + βx^2 acts on an object in the x-direction. The work done by the force is 5 J when the object is displaced by 1 m. If the constant α = 1 N then β will be",
            "options": [
                "15 N/m^2",
                "12 N/m^2",
                "8 N/m^2",
                "10 N/m^2"
            ],
            "answer": "12 N/m^2"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 35,
            "question": "A thin plano convex lens made of glass of refractive index 1.5 is immersed in a liquid of refractive index 1.2. When the plane side of the lens is silver coated for complete reflection, the lens immersed in the liquid behaves like a concave mirror of focal length 0.2 m. The radius of curvature of the curved surface of the lens is",
            "options": [
                "0.20 m",
                "0.25 m",
                "0.15 m",
                "0.10 m"
            ],
            "answer": "0.10 m"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 36,
            "question": "A particle is executing simple harmonic motion with time period 2 s and amplitude 1 cm. If D and d are the total distance and displacement covered by the particle in 12.5 s, then D/d is",
            "options": [
                "16/5",
                "10",
                "15/4",
                "25"
            ],
            "answer": "25"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 37,
            "question": "The amount of work done to break a big water drop of radius R into 27 small drops of equal radius is 10 J. The work done required to break the same big drop into 64 small drops of equal radius will be",
            "options": [
                "15 J",
                "5 J",
                "20 J",
                "10 J"
            ],
            "answer": "15 J"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 38,
            "question": "A plano-convex lens having radius of curvature of first surface 2 cm exhibits focal length of f1 in air. Another plano-convex lens with first surface radius of curvature 3 cm has focal length of f2 when it is immersed in a liquid of refractive index 1.2. If both the lenses are made of same glass of refractive index 1.5, the ratio of f1 and f2 will be",
            "options": [
                "1:2",
                "1:3",
                "3:5",
                "2:3"
            ],
            "answer": "2:3"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 39,
            "question": "An air bubble of radius 0.1 cm lies at a depth of 20 cm below the free surface of a liquid of density 1000 kg/m^3. If the pressure inside the bubble is 2100 N/m^2 greater than the atmospheric pressure, then the surface tension of the liquid in SI unit is (use g=10 m/s^2)",
            "options": [
                "0.1",
                "0.05",
                "0.02",
                "0.25"
            ],
            "answer": "0.05"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 40,
            "question": "A uniform solid cylinder of mass m and radius r rolls along an inclined rough plane of inclination 45°. If it starts to roll from rest from the top of the plane then the linear acceleration of the cylinder's axis will be",
            "options": [
                "1/√2 g",
                "1/(3√2) g",
                "√2 g/3",
                "√2 g"
            ],
            "answer": "√2 g/3"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 41,
            "question": "The Young's double slit interference experiment is performed using light consisting of 480 nm and 600 nm wavelengths to form interference patterns. The least number of the bright fringes of 480 nm light that are required for the first coincidence with the bright fringes formed by 600 nm light is",
            "options": [
                "5",
                "4",
                "6",
                "8"
            ],
            "answer": "5"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 42,
            "question": "A parallel plate capacitor was made with two rectangular plates, each with a length of l=3 cm and breath of b=1 cm. The distance between the plates is 3 μm. Out of the following, which are the ways to increase the capacitance by a factor of 10?",
            "options": [
                "A only",
                "C only",
                "B and D only",
                "C and E only"
            ],
            "answer": "C and E only"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 43,
            "question": "Consider a parallel plate capacitor of area A (of each plate) and separation 'd' between the plates. If E is the electric field and ε₀ is the permittivity of free space between the plates, then potential energy stored in the capacitor is",
            "options": [
                "ε₀ E^2 Ad",
                "(1/2) ε₀ E^2 Ad",
                "(1/4) ε₀ E^2 Ad",
                "(3/4) ε₀ E^2 Ad"
            ],
            "answer": "(1/2) ε₀ E^2 Ad"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 44,
            "question": "An object of mass m is projected from origin in a vertical xy plane at an angle 45° with the x axis with an initial velocity v0. The magnitude and direction of the angular momentum of the object with respect to origin, when it reaches at the maximum height, will be [g is acceleration due to gravity]",
            "options": [
                "(m v0^3)/(2√2 g) along negative z-axis",
                "(m v0^3)/(4√2 g) along positive z-axis",
                "(m v0^3)/(4√2 g) along negative z-axis",
                "(m v0^3)/(2√2 g) along positive z-axis"
            ],
            "answer": "(m v0^3)/(4√2 g) along negative z-axis"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 45,
            "question": "For an experimental expression y=(32.3 × 1125)/27.4, where all the digits are significant. Then to report the value of y we should write",
            "options": [
                "y=1326.19",
                "y=1330",
                "y=1326.186",
                "y=1326.2"
            ],
            "answer": "y=1330"
        }
    ],
    "Chemistry": [
        {
            "question_number": 51,
            "question": "The carbohydrate 'Ribose' present in DNA, is A. A pentose sugar B. present in pyranose from C. in 'D' configuration D. a reducing sugar, when free E. in α-anomeric form Choose the correct answer from the options given below:",
            "options": [
                "A, D and E Only",
                "A, C and D Only",
                "A, B and E Only",
                "B, D and E Only"
            ],
            "answer": "A, C and D Only"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 52,
            "question": "Given below are two statements: Statement I: The conversion proceeds well in the less polar medium. CH3-CH2-CH2-CH2-Cl →[HO^-] CH3-CH2-CH2-CH2-OH + Cl^(-) Statement II: The conversion proceeds well in the more polar medium. CH3-CH2-CH2-CH2-Cl →[R3N] CH3-CH2-CH2-CH2-NR3^+ Cl^(-) In the light of the above statements, choose the correct answer from the options given below",
            "options": [
                "Both Statement I and Statement II are true",
                "Statement I is true but Statement II is false",
                "Statement I is false but Statement II is true",
                "Both Statement I and Statement II are false"
            ],
            "answer": "Both Statement I and Statement II are true"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 53,
            "question": "The product (A) formed in the following reaction sequence is CH3-C≡CH →[i) Hg^2+, H2SO4 ii) HCN iii) H2/Ni] Product (A)",
            "options": [
                "CC(C)(N)CO",
                "CC(C)(O)CN",
                "CCC(O)CN",
                "CCC(N)CO"
            ],
            "answer": "CC(C)(O)CN"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 54,
            "question": "Aman has been asked to synthesise the molecule CC(=O)C1=CCCC1 (x). He thought of preparing the molecule using an aldol condensation reaction. He found a few cyclic alkenes in his laboratory. He thought of performing ozonolysis reaction on alkene to produce a dicarbonyl compound followed by aldol reaction to prepare 'x'. Predict the suitable alkene that can lead to the formation of 'x'.",
            "options": [
                "CC1C=CCCC1",
                "C=C1CCCCC1",
                "CC1=CCCCC1",
                "CC1CC=CCC1"
            ],
            "answer": "CC1=CCCCC1"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 55,
            "question": "Which of the following arrangements with respect to their reactivity in nucleophilic addition reaction is correct?",
            "options": [
                "acetophenone < benzaldehyde < p-tolualdehyde < p-nitrobenzaldehyde",
                "benzaldehyde < acetophenone < p-nitrobenzaldehyde < p-tolualdehyde",
                "p-nitrobenzaldehyde < benzaldehyde < p-tolualdehyde < acetophenone",
                "acetophenone < p-tolualdehyde < benzaldehyde < p-nitrobenzaldehyde"
            ],
            "answer": "acetophenone < p-tolualdehyde < benzaldehyde < p-nitrobenzaldehyde"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 56,
            "question": "Let us consider an endothermic reaction which is non-spontaneous at the freezing point of water. However, the reaction is spontaneous at boiling point of water. Choose the correct option.",
            "options": [
                "Both ΔH and ΔS are (-ve)",
                "ΔH is (-ve) but ΔS is (+ve)",
                "ΔH is (+ve) but ΔS is (-ve)",
                "Both ΔH and ΔS are (+ve)"
            ],
            "answer": "Both ΔH and ΔS are (+ve)"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 57,
            "question": "Preparation of potassium permanganate from MnO2 involves two step process in which the 1st step is a reaction with KOH and KNO3 to produce",
            "options": [
                "K3MnO4",
                "K4[Mn(OH)6]",
                "KMnO4",
                "K2MnO4"
            ],
            "answer": "K2MnO4"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 58,
            "question": "For a reaction, N2O5(g) → 2NO2(g) + 1/2 O2(g) in a constant volume container, no products were present initially. The final pressure of the system when 50% of reaction gets completed is",
            "options": [
                "5 times of initial pressure",
                "5/2 times of initial pressure",
                "7/2 times of initial pressure",
                "7/4 times of initial pressure"
            ],
            "answer": "7/4 times of initial pressure"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 59,
            "question": "One mole of the octahedral complex compound Co(NH3)5Cl3 gives 3 moles of ions on dissolution in water. One mole of the same complex reacts with excess of AgNO3 solution to yield two moles of AgCl(s). The structure of the complex is:",
            "options": [
                "[Co(NH3)4Cl2]·Cl·NH3",
                "[Co(NH3)3Cl3]·2NH3",
                "[Co(NH3)5Cl]Cl2",
                "[Co(NH3)4Cl]·Cl2·NH3"
            ],
            "answer": "[Co(NH3)5Cl]Cl2"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 60,
            "question": "Which of the following ions is the strongest oxidizing agent? (Atomic Number of Ce=58, Eu=63, Tb=65, Lu=71)",
            "options": [
                "Eu2+",
                "Tb4+",
                "Lu3+",
                "Ce3+"
            ],
            "answer": "Tb4+"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 61,
            "question": "Ksp for Cr(OH)3 is 1.6 × 10^{-30}. What is the molar solubility of this salt in water?",
            "options": [
                "1.8 × 10^{-30}/27",
                "(1.8 × 10^{-30})^{1/5}",
                "(1.6 × 10^{-30}/27)^{1/4}",
                "(1.6 × 10^{-30})^{1/2}"
            ],
            "answer": "(1.6 × 10^{-30}/27)^{1/4}"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 62,
            "question": "Which of the following statements are NOT true about the periodic table? A. The properties of elements are function of atomic weights. B. The properties of elements are function of atomic numbers. C. Elements having similar outer electronic configurations are arranged in same period. D. An element's location reflects the quantum numbers of the last filled orbital. E. The number of elements in a period is same as the number of atomic orbitals available in energy level that is being filled. Choose the correct answer from the options given below:",
            "options": [
                "A, C and E Only",
                "A and E Only",
                "B, C and E Only",
                "D and E Only"
            ],
            "answer": "A and E Only"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 63,
            "question": "Given below are two statements I and II. Statement I: Dumas method is used for estimation of 'Nitrogen' in an organic compound. Statement II: Dumas method involves the formation of ammonium sulphate by heating the organic compound with conc H2SO4. In the light of the above statements, choose the correct answer from the options given below",
            "options": [
                "Statement I is true but Statement II is false",
                "Both Statement I and Statement II are false",
                "Statement I is false but Statement II is true",
                "Both Statement I and Statement II are true"
            ],
            "answer": "Statement I is true but Statement II is false"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 64,
            "question": "Which of the following statement is true with respect to H2O, NH3 and CH4? A. The central atoms of all the molecules are sp3 hybridized. B. The H-O-H, H-N-H and H-C-H angles in the above molecules are 104.5°, 107.5° and 109.5°, respectively. C. The increasing order of dipole moment is CH4 < NH3 < H2O. D. Both H2O and NH3 are Lewis acids and CH4 is a Lewis base. E. A solution of NH3 in H2O is basic. In this solution NH3 and H2O act as Lowry-Bronsted acid and base respectively. Choose the correct answer from the options given below:",
            "options": [
                "A, B and C Only",
                "A, D and E Only",
                "C, D and E Only",
                "A, B, C and E Only"
            ],
            "answer": "A, B, C and E Only"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 65,
            "question": "Which one of the carbocations from the following is most stable?",
            "options": [
                "[C+]C=CCO[O+]C",
                "[C+]C=COC",
                "[CH2+]C=CF",
                "[C+]C=COC(C)=O"
            ],
            "answer": "[C+]C=COC"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 66,
            "question": "Following are the four molecules 'P', 'Q', 'R' and 'S'. Which one among the four molecules will react with HBr(aq) at the fastest rate? (P: C1=CCOCC1, Q: C1=COCCC1, R: CC1=CCCCC1, S: CC1=C(C)CCCC1)",
            "options": [
                "R",
                "P",
                "Q",
                "S"
            ],
            "answer": "Q"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 67,
            "question": "For the given cell Fe^{2+}_{(aq)} + Ag^+_{(aq)} → Fe^{3+}_{(aq)} + Ag_{(s)}. The standard cell potential of the above reaction is Ag^+ + e^- → Ag E°=xV. Given: Fe^{2+} + 2e^- → Fe E°=yV. Fe^{3+} + 3e^- → Fe E°=zV.",
            "options": [
                "x+y-z",
                "x+2y",
                "x+2y-3z",
                "y-2x"
            ],
            "answer": "x+2y-3z"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 68,
            "question": "The large difference between the melting and boiling points of oxygen and sulphur may be explained on the basis of",
            "options": [
                "Atomicity",
                "Electron gain enthalpy",
                "Electronegativity",
                "Atomic size"
            ],
            "answer": "Atomicity"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 69,
            "question": "Consider the given plots of vapour pressure (VP) vs temperature(T/K). Which amongst the following options is correct graphical representation showing ΔTf, depression in the freezing point of a solvent in a solution?",
            "options": [
                "(1)",
                "(2)",
                "(3)",
                "(4)"
            ],
            "answer": "(1)"
        },
        {
            "question_number": 70,
            "question": "Which of the following linear combination of atomic orbitals will lead to formation of molecular orbitals in homonuclear diatomic molecules [internuclear axis in z-direction]? A. 2p_z and 2p_x B. 2s and 2p_x C. 3d_xy and 3d_{x^2-y^2} D. 2s and 2p_z E. 2p_z and 3d_{x^2-y^2}",
            "options": [
                "A and B Only",
                "D Only",
                "E Only",
                "C and D Only"
            ],
            "answer": "D Only"
        }
    ]
}